reserveamerica.com 2019-05-21

# Privacy Policy | Aspira

## Overview

RA Outdoors, LLC, doing business as Aspira, and its affiliated companies and subsidiaries (collectively, “Aspira”, “us”, “we”, or “our”) value your privacy and are committed to protecting your personal information. Aspira is a leading provider of software and services for outdoors related activities. In this Privacy Policy (“Policy”), we describe the information that we collect from visitors to and users of our websites (“Sites”), our blogs, our mobile applications (“Applications”), and our online products and services (collectively, “Services”). By visiting our Sites or using any of our Services, you agree that your personal information will be handled as described in this Policy, which is incorporated by reference into our Terms of Use.

If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [privacy@aspiraconnect.com](mailto:privacy@aspiraconnect.com).

## What information do we collect about you and why?

The information we collect from you allows you to log into our Sites and use our Services and Applications. We also collect information from businesses, organizations, and individuals who request information from us.

Individuals may provide us information directly or indirectly by using our Services (these individuals are referred to as “Consumers”). For example, you may enter your information in order to reserve a campsite or purchase a campsite permit or a hunting or fishing license. Relatedly, organizations and entities that use our Services to provide a service to Consumers (our “Clients”) (including agents of our Clients) may provide us with personal information about individuals who have reserved a campsite or purchased a hunting or fishing license or who the Client wants us to contact or otherwise provide Services to on behalf of the Client.

### Information We Collect Directly From You.

 _Account Information for our Sites._  You may browse our Sites without creating an online account or providing us with your information, but to use certain features, you may need to create an account or otherwise provide us with information. When you create an account with us or register for an activity, we may ask you to provide the following:

  * Your first and last name;

  * Your email address and your desired password;

  * Your display name (this is the name other people will see when you post items to one of our Sites or engage in other similar activities on our site);

  * Your date of birth;

  * Your subscription preferences (whether and what types of information you would like us to send you);

  * Information about your activities and interests;

  * Other profile data, such as contact information, occupation, gender and photo; and

  * Payment information, such as credit card or financial account numbers (if applicable).

 _Log in Information for our Sites._  Once you have signed up for a particular Site, on subsequent visits to the same Site, you may simply need to enter your user ID or email address (as applicable) and password to gain access to that Site.

 _Log in and Location Information for our Applications._  When you first visit any of our Applications, you may have the option of creating a user ID and password for subsequent visits. When you log into certain of our Applications, we will request your permission to obtain your current location (so-called “geolocation” information) so that we can provide location-related services, for example, so that we can help you to find a campground, locations to purchase equipment, and other valuable information. In the “settings” function on your phone, you will have the ability to manually permit or preclude us from recording your geolocation information for certain Applications or features of Applications.

 _Contests, Surveys and Questionnaires._  When you sign up for sweepstakes or contests, or complete questionnaires or surveys, we collect information that you submit to us. We use this information to administer the sweepstakes, contest or survey, to analyze the results, for research purposes, to send you other information or offers we think may be of interest to you, to comply with legal requirements, and for other purposes as discussed in this Policy.

 _Licenses, Reservations, Permits, and Fines._  When you purchase hunting or fishing licenses, camping permits, or submit payment for fines, we may require additional information about you in order to complete your request. For example, we may need your driver’s license number, social security number, or visa or passport number in order to verify your identity and process your request. In addition, we might collect public agency reservation information (e.g., information about your planned visit to a specific government agency-operated or government agency-administered campground or park, such as dates of stay or number of occupants, other than personal information). Any such personal information is used only as necessary in order to help complete your transaction.

 _User Profiles, Comments and Posts._  Some of our Sites and Applications may allow users to create or post content, such as comments, profiles, blogs, and messages. If you provide content to our Sites, we may collect and use that information as described in this Policy. Please note that such information may be viewed, collected or used by other registered users and public visitors to our Sites. Once posted, we cannot prevent such information from being used in a manner that may violate this Policy, the law or your personal privacy. Your profile, however, may offer privacy settings within your account to help you manage how your content is displayed.

 _Job Site References._  As part of applying for employment with us, we may ask you for information such as details regarding your education, employment history, qualifications, and the contact information of a former colleague’s name. This information is used for job reference purposes only and is not used for any other purpose.

 _Information We Collect from Facebook._  We may provide you with the opportunity to connect via Facebook, through our Sites or Applications. If you log into Facebook through our Sites or Applications, we will request permission to access your basic information, which includes your name, profile picture, gender, networks, Facebook user ID, list of friends and any other information that you have made public on Facebook. For information about how Facebook may disclose your information, including any information you make public, please consult the Facebook Data Use Policy. We have no control over how Facebook uses or discloses the personal information you provide to it. We store the information that we receive from Facebook along with other information that we collect from you or receive about you.

 _Information We Collect About You From Third Parties._  We also may collect information, including personally identifiable information, about you from our affiliates and non-affiliated third parties.

 _Information We Collect Automatically._  We may use cookies, web beacons, tags, scripts, and other automated devices to collect information, including personally identifiable information, about you when you visit our Sites and receive emails from us. Specifically, we may collect the following information about your use of our Sites via these technologies: your browser type and operating system; web pages you view; links you click; your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address; your approximate geographic location; your interaction with the Sites; length of time you are logged in to our Sites; and websites visited before or after our Sites. In some of our email messages, we use a “click-through URL” linked to content on a Site. When Consumers click one of these URLs, they pass through a separate web server before arriving at the destination page on one of our Sites. We track this click-through data to help us determine interest in particular topics and measure the effectiveness of our Consumer communications. If you prefer not to be tracked in this way, you should not click text or graphic links in the email messages. We also collect non-personal data (including, without limitation, of the type set forth above) from third parties. The information we collect from third parties may be combined with the information we collect. This information also may be associated with your username and combined with other information, including personally identifiable information that we collect about you. For more detailed information on our use of cookies and other tracking technologies, please see our Cookie Policy.

## How do we use your information?

We may use the information that we gather about you for the following purposes:

  * To provide our Services to you, to communicate with you about your use of our Services and for other customer service purposes;

  * To provide information that you have requested to receive from us in response to your opt-in requests;

  * To provide our Services at the request of our Clients;

  * To administer activities on behalf of our Clients;

  * To improve our Sites and Services by providing personalized experiences, location customization, personalized help, and instructions;

  * For marketing and advertising purposes; for example, we may use your information to display targeted advertisements to you on our Sites and to assist us in advertising our Services on third party websites;

  * To send you email, follow-up questions about your activity, news and newsletters, promotions, and/or invitations to visit the Site; and

  * To better understand how users access and use our Sites and Services, both on an aggregated and individualized basis, and for other research purposes.

Clients should note that we may use information we receive or collect regarding Consumers in accordance with the terms of this Policy, including in the manner set forth above. Notwithstanding the foregoing, in certain contexts, we collect information on behalf of our Clients subject to contractual requirements that limit our ability to use and transfer your information in ways that are more narrow than those in this Policy (e.g., the information be only used as necessary to provide Services to the Client and/or for other specified purposes). In those limited circumstances, your information is subject to those contractual requirements and not to this Policy, subject to enforcement by the applicable Client. If your information is collected on behalf of a third party, it will be evident at the time that you provide such information. This Policy does not cover our Clients’ use of your information outside of our Services. You should contact that party directly to determine if your information is subject to such limitations on uses and to ascertain how the third party will make use of your information.

## When and how do we share your information?

 **Third Parties.**  We may share your information, including personally identifiable information, with non-affiliated and affiliated third parties.

 _Affiliates._  We may disclose the information we collect from you to our affiliates or subsidiaries; however, if we do so, their use and disclosure of your information will be subject to this Policy.

 _Clients or Partners._  If you are using our Services to register for an activity or to purchase a third party product or service, we share the personal information that you provide with the applicable third parties in order to fulfill your request. You may receive communications, correspondence, emails, or direct mail from these entities; each such party operates independently from us and is not subject to this Policy but is subject to its own privacy policy. In some instances, we allow Clients to use our email system to contact Consumers, so you may receive emails from our system that originate with such Clients. Please refer to that party’s privacy policy if you have any questions about its use of your information.

 _Service Providers._  We may disclose the information we collect from you to third party vendors, service providers, contractors, or agents who perform functions on our behalf. For example, these providers may help us administer our Sites and Applications, manage and administer activities, or process credit card payments. These third parties have agreed to maintain the confidentiality, security, and integrity of or information and may be located in a location different than where we operate. Where required by law, these companies agree to only use such information for the purposes for which they have been engaged by us unless you expressly permit them to use your information for other purposes.

 _Other Non-Affiliated Third Parties._  We may disclose the information that we collect about you to non-affiliated third parties (with your consent, if consent is required by law), such as promotional partners and others with whom we have marketing or other relationships. Those third parties may use your information for marketing purposes, such as to market products and services that they believe would be of interest to you. We also may combine the information that we collect about you with other information that we obtain from third parties. This information may help us to determine what advertisements to direct to you, to place on our Sites, and where to advertise our Services. As discussed in the advertising section below, you have the ability to opt-out of certain uses of your information. You also have the ability to opt-in to receiving certain information from us and non-affiliated third parties.

 _Supplemental Service Partners._  By purchasing, making reservations, or registering for, products or services offered by third parties as a result of your interaction with the Services or use of the Sites (such as magazine subscriptions), electing to receive communications (such as emails), or electing to participate in contests, sweepstakes, or other programs (such as discount or rewards programs), offered or sponsored by third parties on the Site, you consent to our providing your personal information to those third parties, and you agree that we are not responsible or liable for any of their actions or omissions. Those third parties may use your personal information in accordance with their own privacy policies. You will need to contact those third parties to instruct them directly regarding your preferences for the use of your personal information by them. Additionally, you agree that we will have the right to use and disclose all such information submitted by you to such third parties in the same manner in which we have the right to use and disclose all other information submitted by you directly to us.

 _Strategic Partners._  We have integration relationships with third-party companies and individuals ("Partners"). These relationships extend the functionality of the Services and the Partner’s application or service ("Integrated Service") by allowing the Services and the Integrated Service to exchange Consumer data and to establish linked business processes between the two. Consumers who pay us for use of the Services and use this Integrated Service are considered customers of both Aspira and the Partner. We may share with Partners, and Partners may share with us, Consumer contact, account, financial and billing information, and business data with respect to their integrated business relationship with the Consumer. The sharing of this information allows us and the Partner to establish the identity of the shared customer and determine referral fees owed. This sharing also allows the Partner to provide consolidated billing services to the shared Consumer and allows for the enhanced functionality of the Integrated Service. Information shared for these purposes is governed by this Policy.

 _Affiliate and Referral Partners._  We have referral relationships with third-party companies and individuals ("Referral Partners") who refer their customers to us. We may share with Referral Partners, and Referral Partners may share with us, certain information with respect to a Consumer that is referred by us or a Referral Partner to allow us and the Referral Partner to establish the identity of the shared Consumer and determine referral fees owed.

 _Government Clients._  By making reservations on the Sites for campgrounds, purchasing permits, purchasing hunting or fishing licenses, or using other services provided by government entities, you consent to us sharing your personal information and public agency reservation information with the government agencies and other third parties associated with the registration, purchase, or reservation you are making or service you are using ("Government Agency Partners"). Government Agency Partners may use your personal information and public agency reservation information in accordance with their own privacy policies. You will need to contact those Government Agency Partners who contact you to instruct them directly regarding your preferences for the use of your personal information and public agency reservation information by them.

We also may share your information for the following reasons:

  * Business Transfers. If we are acquired by or merged with another company, if substantially all of our assets are transferred to another company, or as part of a bankruptcy proceeding, we may transfer the information we have collected from you to the acquiring company. You acknowledge and agree that any successor to or acquiror will continue to have the right to use your information in accordance with the terms of this Policy.

  * In Response to Legal Process. We also may disclose the information we collect from you in order to comply with the law, a judicial proceeding, court order or other legal process, such as in response to a subpoena.

  * To Protect Ourselves and Others. We also may disclose the information we collect from you where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person or violations of our Terms of Use or this Policy.

  * Aggregate and Anonymized Information. We may share aggregate or anonymized information about Consumers with third parties for marketing, advertising, research or similar purposes. For example, if we display advertisements on behalf of a third party, we may share aggregate, demographic information with that third party about the Consumers to whom we displayed the advertisements.

 **Third Party Applications.**  Third party applications, such as Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest, or Google buttons, may be available on our Sites. The owners or providers of those third party applications may collect personally identifiable information from you. Their collection of information is bound by their own information collection policies and practices. Your interactions with third party applications on our Sites may be shared with others within your social network. We are not responsible for the collection and use of your information by third parties.

Our Sites may include social media features, such as a Facebook “Like” button and widgets such as the “share this button” or interactive mini-programs. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing such feature.

 **Network Advertisers.**  Network advertisers are third parties that display advertisements based on your visits to our Sites and other websites you have visited. This enables us and these third parties to target advertisements to you for products and services in which you might be interested. These third party services may use cookies, JavaScript, web beacons (including clear GIFs), and other technologies to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content to you. These third party technologies are governed by each third party’s specific privacy policy, not this one. We may provide these third parties with information, including both personally identifiable and non-personally identifiable information, about your usage of our Sites and our Services. For more detailed information on the use of third party technologies and how to opt-out of receiving targeted advertisements, please see our Cookie Policy.

We use Local Storage, such as HTML5, to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our website or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity may also use HTML5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5.

 **Third Party Links.**  At times, our Sites and Applications may contain links to other third party websites. Any access to and use of such linked websites is not governed by this Policy, but, instead, is governed by the privacy policies of those third party websites, and we are not responsible for the information practices of such third party websites.

## How secure is information about me?

We have implemented commercially reasonable precautions, including, where appropriate, password protection, encryption, and secure socket layering to protect our Sites and the information we collect from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. Please be aware that despite our efforts, no data security measures can guarantee 100% security all of the time. Please keep this in mind when disclosing any of your personal information via our Sites.

You should take steps to protect against unauthorized access to your password, computer, and web-enabled devices, among other things, by signing off after using a shared computer, inserting a password on your web-enabled device, choosing a password that nobody else knows or can easily guess, keeping your password private, and periodically changing your password. You should never share your log-in information with others. We are not responsible for any lost, stolen or compromised passwords, or for any activity on your account via unauthorized password activity.

## Can I access and modify my personal information?

Upon request, we will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your personal information.  To request this information please e-mail us at [privacy@aspiraconnect.com](mailto:privacy@aspiraconnect.com).

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, delete/remove, or ask to have it removed from a public forum or testimonial by making the change within your account settings or by contacting us via one of the methods listed in this Policy. We will respond to your request to access within 30 days. Please note that copies of information that you have updated, modified, or deleted may continue to reside in our systems for a period of time. In the event we are unable to complete your access request, we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. We may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, are extremely impractical, or for which access is not otherwise required by local law.

If your information has been shared with a third party, as described above, or collected on behalf of a Client, then that third party has received their own copy of your data. If you have been contacted by one of these third parties, or one of our Clients, and wish to correct or request they delete your information, please contact them directly.

## What choices do I have regarding my information?

We may send you emails from time-to-time, for example, to ask you about an activity in which you participated. When you use our Services, you may have the option of signing up for news and offers from us or other third parties, which may include, information about activities, our newsletter or other items that we (or third parties) believe may be of interest to you. If, at any time, you would like to stop receiving the information that you have requested to receive from us, you may follow the opt-out instructions contained in any such e-mail. Please note that it may take up to 10 business days for us to process opt-out requests.

To opt-out of products, programs, Services or offers from our affiliates and trusted partners, please contact [privacy@aspiraconnect.com](mailto:privacy@aspiraconnect.com) or log into your account and update your subscription preferences. If you opt-out of receiving emails or promotions from us, we still may send you e-mails about your account or any Services you have requested or received from us, or for other customer services purposes. In addition, you may still receive emails sent by our Clients through means other than our system. Further, if you opt-out of receiving information related to a particular activity, you will still receive communications from us and communications related to other activities. So you may have to unsubscribe from multiple emails before you stop receiving all communications related to activities for which you registered through our Services. Note that you cannot unsubscribe from update communications about the Services unless you close your account.

If you wish to not have your personal information shared with third parties for the creation and display of targeted advertisements, you will need to close your account. This action may be possible through the settings within your account or by contacting us at [privacy@aspiraconnect.com](mailto:privacy@aspiraconnect.com).

By electing to stop receiving all communications from us or through our system you will no longer receive any updates on your account or on activities you are registered to participate in or have previously participated in, including communications regarding refunds. We do not recommend that you do this unless you plan to no longer use the Services. Even after you opt-out of all communications, we will retain your information in accordance with this Policy, however, we will no longer use it to contact you. However, our Clients who have received your information in accordance with this Policy may still use that information to contact you in accordance with their own privacy policies, but they may not use our system to do so.

If you would like to delete your account with us, you may do so by emailing us at [info@aspiraconnect.com](mailto:info@aspiraconnect.com) and specifying which account(s) to delete.

## Notice to international visitors

Our Sites, Applications, and Services are controlled and operated by us from the United States, and are not intended to subject us to the laws or jurisdiction of any state, country or territory other than the United States. Your personal information may be stored and processed in any country where we have facilities or in which we engage service providers. By using our Sites, Applications, and/or Services, you consent to the transfer of information to countries outside of your country of residence, including the United States, which may have different data protection rules than those of your country.

## Children's Privacy

Our Sites, Applications, and Services are not directed to or intended for use by minors. Consistent with the requirements of the US Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act, if we learn that we have received information directly from a child under age 13 without his or her parent or legal guardian’s verified consent, we will use that information only to respond directly to that child (or his or her parent or legal guardian) to inform the child that he or she cannot create an account or otherwise use the Services. Subsequently, we will make commercially reasonable efforts to delete such information.

## Terms of Use

Your use of our Sites or Services, as well as any dispute over privacy, is subject to this Policy and our Terms of Use, including applicable limitations on damages and the resolution of disputes.

## Special notice to California residents

 _ **California “Shine the Light” Request.**_  California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits individual California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of certain categories of personal information to third parties for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes. You may make no more than one such request per calendar year. In your request, please attest to the fact that you are a California resident and provide a current California address for your response. You may request this information in writing by contacting us at:

Attn: Aspira Privacy  
RA Outdoors, LLC, d/b/a Aspira  
717 North Harwood Street  
Suite 2400  
Dallas, TX 75201  
Email: [privacy@aspiraconnect.com](mailto:privacy@aspiraconnect.com)

We reserve our right not to respond to requests submitted other than to the email or mailing addresses specified in this Section.

## Changes to this policy

We may change this Policy from time to time, so be sure to check back periodically. If we make any changes to this Policy that materially affect our practices with regard to the personal information we have previously collected from you, we will endeavor to notify you in advance of such change, by highlighting the change on the Sites or by sending an email to you at the email address that you have registered with us. Your continued use of the Services after any changes or revisions to this Policy will indicate your agreement with the terms of the revised Policy.

## Contact Us

We regularly review our practices regarding personally identifiable information and this Policy. If you have any questions, comments or concerns, please contact us at:

Attn: Aspira Privacy  
RA Outdoors, LLC, d/b/a Aspira  
717 North Harwood Street  
Suite 2400  
Dallas, TX 75201  
Email: [privacy@aspiraconnect.com](mailto:privacy@aspiraconnect.com)
